这张是小班在打瞌睡
Here's little Ben nodding off.
摩妮卡姑姑的小宝贝哟
Aww, look at Aunt Monica's little boy.
- 他的发型跟罗斯一样耶   - 给我看
- Look, he's got Ross' haircut.     - Oh, let me see.
天啊 他真是超可爱的
Oh, God! Is he just the sweetest thing?
让人想亲遍他全身
You must just want to kiss him all over.
这点子真不赖
That would be nice.
- 噗…   - 什么？
- Pfft.     - Pardon?
没事 我只是在吐气而已
Nothing. Just a little extra air in my mouth. Pfft.
钱德 帮我付一下吧？我再还你钱
Hey, Chan, can you help me out here? I promise I'll pay you back.
好 加上上礼拜的松饼钱
Oh, yeah, right. Including the waffles last week...
你已经欠我…
...you now owe me...
十七块的几百万倍
...17 jillion dollars.
真的 我这次一定会还你
I will, really, I'll pay you back this time.
你的钱从哪儿来？
Where's the money coming from?
我现在在纽约大学医学院帮忙做研究
I'm helping out at the NYU Med School with some, uh, research.
什么研究？
What kind of research?
就是科学研究嘛
Uh, just, you know, science.
科学
Science.
喔 我好像听过
Yeah, I think I've heard of that.
是不孕症的研究
It's a fertility study.
乔伊
Joey...
请告诉我 你只捐献时间
Please tell me you're only donating your time.
拜托 又没什么大不了的
Come on, you guys. It's not that big a deal.
我只是每隔一天去那边…
I just go down there every other day...
做出一点贡献
...and make my contribution to the project.
两个礼拜就可以赚七百块耶
Hey, but at the end of two weeks, I get $700!
哇 你动几根手指就有钱赚了
Wow, you're gonna be making money hand over fist.
沙拉跟面包都有了
Okay, we got the coleslaw. We got the buns.
还有用可爱的牛跟火鸡做的新鲜绞肉
We've got the ground-up flesh of formally cute cows and turkeys.
男人们来啰
Men are here!
我们来升火
We make fire.
烤肉
Cook meat.
然后用尿把火浇熄 之后就再也不会被邀请了
Then put out fire by peeing, no get invited back!
好可爱喔
Cute, cute.
- 梅兰妮打电话来说她会晚点到   - 好
- Oh, Melanie called. She's gonna be late.     - Oh, okay.
你们进展如何？
So how are things going with you two?
她快变成你的另一半了没？
Is she becoming your special someone?
我也不知道 她还蛮不错的
I don't know. She's, uh... She's pretty great.
她对你参加科学实验有意见吗？
Yeah? What does she think of your little science project?
你以为我会跟女伴说 我同时也在跟杯子约会吗？
You think I'm gonna tell a girl I like that I'm also seeing a cup?
这家伙说的有道理
The man's got a point.
问题是她真的很想跟我上床
Well, the tough thing is, she really wants to have sex with me.
真是个疯女人
Crazy bitch.
实验还有一个礼拜才结束 根据规定…
I still got a week left in the program, and according to the rules...
想拿钱 就不能私底下进行实验
...if I want to get the money, I'm not allowed to conduct any personal experiments...
- 你们知道我的意思吧   - 乔伊 我们一直都懂
- ...if you know what I mean.     - Joey, we always know what you mean.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey. Hey.
你以为烤肉会烤多久？
How long did you think this barbecue was gonna last?
我要去中国
I'm going to China.
天啊 才刚说一件事…
Jeez, you say one thing and, eh...
你要去中国？
You're going to China?
为了博物馆的事 有人发现化石
It's, uh, for the museum. Someone found a bone.
我们想要化石 可是他们不想给我们化石
We want the bone, they don't want us to have it.
所以我要去那边说服他们 都是化石惹的祸
So I'm going to try to persuade them... It's a whole big "bone" thing.
总之我要去一个礼拜
Anyway, I'm gonna be gone for, like, a week.
如果你要联络上我 那是不可能的 这是我的行程
So, uh, if you wanna reach me, you can't. So here's my itinerary.
呃…
Um...
- 这是我的照片   - 喔 我看看
- Here's a picture of me.     - Oh, let me see.
可以叫卡萝时不时拿给小班看吗？这样他才不会忘了我
Could you take it to Carol's now and then and show it to Ben so he doesn't forget me?
- 当然   - 嗨 小班
- Yeah.     - Hi, Ben.
我是你爸爸
I'm your father.
我是大头
I am The Head! Pahh!
这次的烤肉一定会很好玩
This barbecue's gonna be very fun.
瑞秋在吗？我想在离开前祝她生日快乐
Is Rachel here? Um, I wanted to wish her a happy birthday before I left.
- 她跟卡尔出去喝点东西了   - 哦
- Oh, no, she's out having drinks with Carl.     - Oh. Heh.
卡尔是谁？
Hey, who's Carl?
- 就是在咖啡厅碰到的一个男的   - 不清楚
- The guy she met at the coffeehouse?     - No.
- 是一个男的 咖啡厅碰到的   - 在咖啡厅碰到的？对
- See, there's this guy she met at...     - The coffeehouse? Right.
你知道那个人是谁嘛
So you do know who he is. Heh.
好 我要去跟男生们道别
I'm gonna go say goodbye to the guys.
跟他们说化石的事情
Hey, you know what? Tell them that bone story.
- 嗨   - 嘿
- Hi.     - Hey.
嘿
Hey.
- 我得去中国一趟   - 你是说那个国家吗？
- I have to go to China.     - The country?
错 是我妈妈橱柜上的那堆碗盘
No, this big pile of dishes in my Mom's breakfront.
你知道卡尔是谁吗？
Do you guys know who Carl is?
我想想 艾尔文 赛门 席尔多…
Let's see. Alvin, Simon, Theodore...
不认识
No.
- 瑞秋今晚跟他去喝酒   - 哦 不
- Well, Rachel's having drinks with him.     - Oh, no!
她怎么可以这样？而且对你一点兴趣也没有
How can she, when she's never shown interest in you?
忘了她吧
Forget about her.
他说得对 你要忘了她
He's right, man. Please move on.
快点去中国吧 去吃些好吃的中国菜
Go to China. Eat Chinese food.
当然中国人不会说自己吃的是"中国菜"
Of course, there they just call it food.
大概吧 我不知道
Yeah? I guess. I don't know.
好吧 那就帮我把这个交给她 好吗？
All right, just give her this for me, okay?
老兄 我们是为了你好
Listen, we're just looking out for you.
- 我知道   - 希望你能开心
- I know.     - We want you to be happy.
虽然我喝了点啤酒 可是我是爱你的喔
And I may only have a couple beers in me, but I love you, man.
我还在喝第一瓶
I'm still on my first.
我觉得你是个好人
I just think you're nice.
我们是那时候开始经营水果篮生意的
Anyway, that's when me and my friends started this fruit-basket business.
我们称自己为"篮子三剑客"
We call ourselves "The Three Basketeers." Ha, ha.
就是 "三剑客" 加上水果
Like "The Three Musketeers," only with fruit.
哦
Oh!
好
Okay.
- 你们的汉堡肉要多熟？ - 不 先拆礼物 食物等一等
- How do you like your burgers?     - No. Presents first, food later!
等一下 小老虎
Hold on there, tiger.
你还好吧？还撑得下去吗？
How's it going? How you holding up?
不太好
Well, not so good.
她以为我们今晚会进展到全垒打的地步
She thinks tonight's the night we're gonna complete the transaction...
如果你知道…
...if you know what I...
你知道的嘛
And you do. Heh.
你有想过就陪在她身边吗？
So, uh, have you ever thought about being there for her?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你知道 就是单纯的陪伴在她身边
You know, just be there for her.
我听不懂耶
Not following you.
好好想想吧
Think about it.
我想这个是来自…
Okay, I'm guessing this is from...
梅兰妮 谢谢你
Well, thank you, Melanie.
- 这个是我送的   - 好的
- Okay, this one right here is from me.     - Okay.
好 很轻
Hmm. Ah, it's light.
有沙沙声 是…
It rattles. It's...
- 拼字游戏随身包   - 嘿
- ...Travel Scrabble.     - Ha, ha, hey!
谢谢
Wow. Thank you.
这是乔伊送的
This one's from Joey.
感觉像是书 应该是书 真的是一本书
It feels like a book. I think it's a book. Feels like a book. And it's a book!
是苏西博士
It's Dr. Seuss!
那本书伴我度过许多艰难的日子
That book got me through some tough times.
这男人心中住着一个小孩
There is a little child inside this man.
医生说如果把孩子从他身体里拿走 他会死的
The doctors say if they remove it, he'll die.
- 这是谁送的？ - 是罗斯送的
- Who's this from?     - That's, uh, Ross'.
啊
Ah.
天啊
Oh, my God.
他还记得
He remembered.
记得什么？
Remembered what?
是几个月前的事了
It was, like, months ago.
我们经过一家古董店 我看到这枚胸针
We were walking by this antique store, and I saw this pin in the window.
我跟他说这枚胸针 跟我小时候奶奶的胸针很像
I told him it was just like one my grandmother had when I was little.
真不敢相信 他竟然还记得
Aw! I can't believe he remembered!
可是你能在飞机上玩那个吗？
Well, sure, but can you play it on a plane?
好美喔
Oh, it's so pretty.
- 一定花了他很多钱   - 真是不敢相信
- This must've cost him a fortune.     - I can't believe he did this.
你们记得上大学时 罗斯爱上卡萝…
Ross? Remember when he fell in love with Carol...
买给她一个超贵的水晶鸭吗？
...and bought her that ridiculously expensive crystal duck?
你刚说什么？
What did you just say?
水晶鸭
Crystal duck.
不是 不是
No, no, no.
爱上卡萝的那段
The, um... The "love" part?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
很好 继续抓头啊
That's good. Just keep rubbing your head.
这样就可以收回你说的话
That'll turn back time.
这真是太难以置信了
This is unbelievable. I mean, this is unbelievable.
是啊 这真是超级大条的事情
I know. This is really, really huge.
不 这是小事 微不足道的超级小事
No, it's not. It's small, it's tiny, it's petite, it's wee.
我们的生活从此面临巨大转变
Uh-uh. I don't think any of our lives will ever be the same ever again.
想办法让这女人闭嘴好吗？
Is there a mute button on this woman?
我觉得这样很棒 你跟罗斯在一起很棒
I think this is so great! I mean, you and Ross!
- 你之前知道吗？ - 不知道
- Did you have any idea?     - No, none.
我到纽约的第一个晚上 他说过要约我出去…
My first night in the city, he mentioned asking me out...
可是一直都没有发生 所以我以为…
...but nothing ever happened, so I just...
他还说了什么？他有说想跟我约会吗？
What else did he say? Does he want to go out with me?
他既然那么爱你…
Given that he's desperately in love with you...
应该不介意跟你喝杯咖啡吧
...he wouldn't mind getting a cup of coffee or something.
罗斯？
Ross?
他一直都喜欢我？
All this time?
- 我得去找他谈谈   - 他人在中国啊
- I've gotta talk to him.     - He's in China!
他指的是国家喔
The country.
等等 他的班机四十五分钟后才起飞
Wait, his flight doesn't leave for 45 minutes.
那时差呢？从这儿到机场的时差？
What about the time difference? From here to the airport?
没错
Yes!
- 你赶不及的   - 我总得试试
- You're never gonna make it!     - I've got to try.
瑞秋 你要对他说什么？
What are you gonna say to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
那你就不该去
Maybe you shouldn't go.
对 如果你是去伤他的心 那就不用急于一时
Right, because if you're gonna break his heart, that can wait.
对 但如果是好消息 那就马上去告诉他
Yeah, but if it's good news, tell him now.
搞不好等我看到他就会知道
Maybe I'll know when I see him.
好吧 这样有帮助吗？
Here, look. All right, does this help?
没有
No.
我只知道我等不了一个礼拜 这件事太让人震撼了
All I know is, I cannot wait a week. This is just too big.
我得跟他谈谈…
I've just got to talk to him. I've got...
- 待会儿见了   - 瑞秋 我爱你
- I'll see you later.     - Rachel, I love you!
先跟我谈啊
Deal with me first!
好
All right.
罗斯 罗斯
Ross! Ross.
不好意思 借过
Excuse me, pardon me.
- 您的登机证呢？ - 嗨
- Hi. Your boarding pass?     - Hi.
我没有登机证 我只是有事得跟我朋友谈谈
No, I need to talk to my friend.
抱歉 没有登机证就无法进去
Sorry, you're not allowed on the jetway unless you have a boarding pass.
他刚进去 就在那里 穿蓝色外套的那个 我可以…
He just went on. He's right there, in the blue jacket! Can I just...?
抱歉 这是联邦法律规定
I'm sorry. Federal regulations!
好 那你可以帮我传话吗？
All right, um, then could you please just give him a message for me?
拜托 我有重要的事跟他说
Please? This is very important.
好吧 你想说什么？
All right. What's the message?
我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
不好意思 先生 先生？
Excuse me! Sir! Excuse me! Sir?
- 有人请我传话给你   - 是什么？
- I have a message for you.     - What?
瑞秋说她很喜欢你送的礼物 她会等你回来
It's from Rachel. She loved the present. She'll see you when you get back.
什么？
What?
托碧 我不知道她在说什么
Toby, I don't know what she's talking about.
没有瑞秋这个女人
There's no Rachel!
不要跟我冷战
Don't give me that deep freeze!
噢 乔伊…
Oh, Joey, Joey, Joey!
我想我刚失去了知觉
I think I blacked out there for a minute.
这不算什么啦
It was nothing.
现在换你享受啰
Well, now we gotta find something fun for you!
等等
Ahh, you know what?
别管我了 你再来一次吧
Forget about me. Let's, uh... Let's give you another turn.
我再一次？
Me, again?
有何不可？
Sure. Why not?
哇 有人明天会拿到一个超大的水果篮
Boy! Somebody's gonna get a big fruit basket tomorrow!
我得说 乔伊 你跟我想象中的完全不一样
I gotta tell you, you are nothing like I thought you would be.
什么意思？
How do you mean?
我以为你是凡事只想到自己的男人
I just had you pegged as one of those guys who are always, "Me, me, me!"
- 哈   - 可是你…
- Ha, ha.     - But you...
竟然这么替别人着想
...you're a giver.
你是我见过最大方体贴的男人
You're, like, the most generous man I ever met.
你根本就是个女人
I mean, you're practically a woman.
瑞秋 你要把包装纸留起来吗？
So, uh, Rach, do you want to save this wrapping paper?
只有点破
It's only a little torn.
你想跟罗斯在一起吗？还是我该把这东西给丢了？
Are you gonna go for it with Ross, or should I throw it out?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我去的时候一直在想…
Thought about it all of the way there...
回来的时候也一直想…
...and I thought about it all the way back and, uh...
竟然是罗斯
You know, it's Ross!
你们知道我的意思吗？我跟罗斯耶
You know what I mean? It's Ross.
- 是啊   - 是啊
- Sure!     - Sure.
我不知道 我的直觉告诉我…
I don't know. This is just my initial gut feeling...
我想
...but I'm thinking...
这样应该会很棒
...it'd be really great.
天啊 我也这样觉得耶 我们会变成朋友兼亲家
Oh, my God, me too! Oh, we'd be like friends-in-law!
最棒的是 你对他已经很了解
The best part is you already know everything about him.
感觉就像第十五次约会
It's like starting on the 15th date.
对啊 一开始就像已经约会十五次了一样
But it would be like starting on the 15th date.
说的好
Another good point.
我的意思是…
No, I mean...
通常约会到第十五次 双方就应该已经在交往
At the 15th date, you're already in a "relationship-y" place.
确定要在一起了
You're committed.
唔…
Huh.
如果事情不成怎么办？
What happens if it doesn't work out?
- 为什么会不成？ - 不知道 有时候就是会这样
- Why isn't it working out?     - I don't know, sometimes it doesn't.
他不够帅吗？还是赚的钱不够多？
Is he not cute enough for you? Does he not make enough money?
- 不是啦 我只是…   - 也许她有别的对象
- No, I'm just...     - Maybe there's someone else.
是吗？你还有别的对象吗？
Is there? Is there someone else?
- 没有啊 没有别人   - 那你…
- No, there is no one else.     - Then why the hell...
- 干嘛甩掉我哥？ - 什…
- ...are you dumping my brother?     - Wha...?
- 嘿 大…   - 嘘
- Hey, big...     - Shh!
慈善家
Spender.
她还在睡觉
She's still asleep.
- 结果怎样？ - 太神奇了
- So how'd it go?     - It was amazing.
你知道那种自认很行的感觉吗？
You know how you think you're great in bed?
你会问我那种问题 就代表你根本不了解我
The fact you'd even ask shows how little you know me.
昨晚我没办法表现...
Well, it's like, last night I couldn't do the thing...
拿手的技巧
...that usually makes me great.
所以我只好想别的办法
So I had to do all this other stuff.
结果我得到的回应超赞 老兄 不是我自夸
And the response I got! Man, oh, man.
好像去参加碎纸花游行一样开心
It was like a ticker-tape parade!
我知道 我房间离游行路线非常非常近
Yes I know. As it happens, my room is very close to the parade route.
那种感觉真的很棒 不只是她 我也觉得超赞的
It was amazing, and not just for her. Uh-uh. For me too.
那种感觉就像是 我突然间看不见了…
It's like, all of a sudden, I'm blind...
可是其他的感官却都变敏锐
...but all my other senses are heightened.
我好像可以体会到…
You know? It's like, I was able to appreciate it...
另一种层次的喜悦
...on another level.
我不知道你还有层次感官
I didn't know you had another level.
对啊 我之前也不知道
I know. Neither did I!
- 哇 这件裙子真漂亮 是你的生日礼物吗？ - 是的
- Hey, great skirts! Birthday present?     - Yeah.
- 谁送的？ - 你送的
- From who?     - From you.
我把你送的衬衫拿去换了
I exchanged the blouse you got me.
心意最重要
Well, it's the thought.
罗斯的班机不是快到了吗？
Doesn't Ross' flight get in in a couple hours?
我记得是在登机门27B
At gate 27B?
对
Uh, yeah.
摩妮卡 我想了很久
Monica, you know, I've been thinking about it.
我觉得我不该跟罗斯在一起
I've decided this Ross thing is not a good idea.
- 为什么？ - 因为我会觉得
- Why?     - Because I feel...
我不只是在跟他交往
...like I wouldn't just be going out with him.
你们大家都会变成我约会的对象
I would be going out with all of you.
- 我会有压力…   - 没有压力 没有压力的
- Ugh, there'd be all this pressure and...     - No pressure, no pressure!
摩妮卡 我们八字都还没一撇 你就已经这么…
Nothing has even happened yet and you're already so...
我哪有 好吧
I'm not "so."
一开始我是觉得有点怪…
I was a teensy bit weird at first...
可是我发誓不会给你们压力
...but I'll be good. I promise.
是谁？
Who is it?
是我 卡尔
It's me, Carl.
上来吧
Come on up.
你背着我哥偷吃？
Behind my brother's back?
像这种话 我绝不可能会对你说的
Is the kind of crazy thing you won't be hearing from me.
- 七百块   - 太棒了 你办到了
- Seven hundred bucks.     - All right, you did it.
家里有水果吗？
Do we have any fruit?
真是可怕的两个礼拜
Man, hell of a two weeks, huh?
你知道吗？我觉得我从中学到很多
You know what, though? I really feel I learned something.
你还要继续"凡事以她为主"吗？
So you'll stick with this "it's all for her" thing?
你疯了吗？
What, are you crazy?
一个盲人恢复视觉之后 还会这样走路吗？
When a blind man gets his sight back, does he walk around like this?
我只是说 如果再让我看到…
I'm just saying, if I see one more picture of Ed Begley Jr...
艾德•贝格利在电动车里的照片
...in that stupid electric car...
我就会自杀
...I'm gonna shoot myself!
我并不是反对环保…
Don't get me wrong. I'm not against environmental issues, per se...
我只是讨厌那个家伙
...it's just that guy!
没想到你竟然宁愿跟他出去 而不是我
I can't believe you'd rather go out with him than me.
抱歉 我正在约会耶
Excuse me, please. I'm trying to have a date here.
好 那就停止想我啊
Fine, just stop thinking about me.
做不到是吧？
Can't do it, can you?
我是在想你 那又怎样？
So I'm thinking about you. So what?
我不懂 这个男人到底哪里好？
I don't get it. What do you see in this guy anyway?
他似乎是一个好人
Well, he seems to be a very nice guy.
拜托 你好歹也买部真正的车吧
I mean, come on, buddy! Get a real car!
瑞秋 给我们一个机会吧
Rachel, come on. Give us a chance.
- 罗斯 这对我来说太难了   - 不…
- Ross, it's too hard.     - No, no.
为什么？因为大家会觉得很怪吗？
Because it'll get weird for everyone else?
这是我们两人的事
Who cares about them? This is about us.
我从初三就开始喜欢你了
I've been in love with you since the ninth grade.
- 罗斯 你算是我最好的朋友   - 我知道
- You're, like, my best friend.     - I know.
- 如果我们分手 而我失去你的话…   - 哇
- If we broke up, and I lost you...     - Whoa.
你为什么会这么想？
Why do you think we'll break up?
你有谈过没分手的恋爱吗？
Have you been involved with someone where you haven't broken up?
没有
No.
可是这种事只需要发生一次
But it only has to happen once.
我们都知道我们是天生一对
You and I know we are perfect for each other.
对不对？
Right?
所以唯一的问题是 你喜欢我吗？
So the only question is: Are you attracted to me?
我不知道
I don't know.
我从来没把你看成恋爱对象
I mean, I've never looked at you that way before.
那就从现在开始吧
Well start looking.
哇
Wow.
没错
Exactly!
这个白痴会害我…
And you just know I'm gonna be the guy...
塞在车阵中的
...caught behind this hammerhead in traffic!
- 对   - 嘿
- Right.     - Heh.
你说的对
You're right.
- 你知道吗？ - 什么？
- You know what?     - What?
我刚想到我得去机场接朋友
I forgot, I'm supposed to pick up a friend at the airport.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry. I'm so...
如果你想留在这里把这喝完 请自便
If you want to stay and finish your drinks, please do.
抱歉 我得走了 抱歉
I'm sorry, I gotta go. I'm sorry.
可是…
But...
抱歉 借过 抱歉
Excuse me! Pardon me! Excuse me.
不好意思
I'm sorry. Ha, ha.
托碧 拜托 你别这样好吗？
Toby, for God's sake, will you let it go?
根本没有瑞秋这个女人
There's no Rachel!
- 嘿 我来拿   - 哦
- Oh, hey. I got that.     - Oh.
- 谢谢 甜心   - 不客气
- Thanks, sweetie.     - No problem.
我等不及要把你介绍给朋友们
I cannot wait for you to meet my friends.
是吗？你觉得他们不会批判挖苦我吗？
Really? You don't think they'll judge and ridicule me?
他们会 可是我…
No, they will. I just, uh...
- 就是等不及   - 等不及
- Can't wait. Heh.     - Can't wait.
得了 他们一定会喜欢你的
Come on, they're gonna love you.